

mrh258@live.se | 0763448444 | https://raquibul-258.github.io/Portfolio/ |

# Summary

Talented web and video editor with 5 years of experience. I have good knowledge of HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 5, and JavaScript (ES6) as well as work experience with 2D graphics (Adobe Illustrator, Canva), CMS (WordPress, Elementor Pro), CRM, video editing tools (Canva, Invideo Ai, MS Clipchamp). My long experience in the graphic industry has given me a great advantage as a front-end developer and web editor. My rich language skills are an added advantage when it comes to working with clients and in an international environment.

# Experience -

FOLKBRO AB | Kista, Stockholm Web Content Manager 06/2023 - 12/2023

- Developed and implemented web content strategies to ensure effective communication and presentation of information.
- Created (content and format) more than 10 commercial videos for company websites and digital marketing.
- Reviewed existing web content for accuracy, relevance, timeliness, completeness, and consistency in style and formatting.

Kista, Sweden

**Executive Director** 02/2009 - 05/2023

- TULIP REKLAM (4R PRODUCTION HB) | Developed graphics, logos, and layouts for product illustrations, company logos, and websites.
  - Managed multiple projects simultaneously while meeting tight deadlines.
  - Designed print materials such as brochures, flyers, and posters for marketing campaigns.

NRJ REKLAM SIA | Riga, Latvia **Account Manager** 01/2003 - 08/2008

- Collaborated with creative teams on the development of advertising materials.
- Organized and managed multiple projects simultaneously while meeting deadlines.
- Worked closely with clients to develop effective ad copy that meets their needs.

# **Education and Training**

THE APP BREWERY | London, UK

THE COMPLETE WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP (ONLINE COURSE)

Expected in 06/2024

• Completed coursework in HTML, Advanced CSS, Bootstrap 5

ABF VUXENUTBILDNING STOCKHOLM | Stockholm, Sweden SWEDISH AS A SECOND LANGUAGE (SAS) in Swedish 12/2011

• Completed coursework in Swedish reading, writing, and speaking at an advanced high school level.

#### RIGA AVIATION UNIVERSITY | Riga, Latvia

#### **BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE**

05/1996

- Completed coursework in basic programming languages (Basic, Assembler, C++, etc.), electronics and radio electronics, computer networking, etc.
- Major in Computer networking

## TBILISI STATE UNIVERSITY (GEORGIA) | Tbilisi, Georgia

#### RUSSIAN AS A SECOND LANGUAGE in Russian Studies

06/1991

• Completed continuing education in the Russian language medium at the University level.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Coding HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 5, JavaScript (ES 6)
- Graphics Adobe Illustrator, Canva
- CMS Word Press
- CRM Bitrix24
- Digital & Offset printing
- Packaging design & production
- Social media marketing (LinkedIn, Meta Business Suit)

## Languages -

Bengali: First Language

English:	C2	Russian:	C1
Proficient (C2)		Advanced (C1)	
Swedish:	C1	Arabic:	B1
Advanced (C1)		Intermediate (B1)	
Latvian:	B1	Urdu:	A2
Intermediate (B1)		Elementary (A2)	
Hindi:	A2		
Elementary (A2)			

## **Personal Information**

- Title: Front-End Web Developer
- Date of Birth: 10/21/72
- Nationality: Swedish, Bangladeshi
- Driving License: B (Swedish)

#### **Hobbies and Interests** -

- Traveling
- Training
- Sports (Volleyball, badminton, table tennis, chess, etc.)

#### References

References available upon request.